#### Paulo Leonardo Benatto

Brighton, UK benatto@gmail.com Phone: +44 07533998484 Post Code: BN21HF

### Summary

My name is Paulo Leonardo Benatto, aka Patito, a Brazillian software developer that resembles a hobbit \_o/. I graduated in Computer Science in 2008, however, I have been working with Linux since 2002. I started with Debian Potato (mount /dev/fd0 =), good times!

After university I moved to Florianopolis, a city in south Brazil, where I started working as a Jr. Software Developer. Since then I have worked in several companies using different technologies, such as: C/C++, Python, JavaScript, Linux and so on.

In 2014, I decided to leave Brazil and try a new experience in England, make new friends and drink some pints. I started working as busser at Planet Hollywood. It was a fun job, but hard in the same time. After 2 months working in Planet Hollywood, Brandwatch invited me to hold a position as Linux System Administrator and I had a chance to learn a lot about the sysadmin/devops world.

At the end of last year I began learning the Go programming language, I bought some books, attended a Go conference and started following the Go community. This year I was given the opportunity to work at Sainsburys Digital Labs where I'm developing microservices in GoLang.

I believe I am a good mood person that enjoys working in agile teams and open-minded companies. I also consider myself hardworking with can-do attitude and I really like to learn and share knowledge.

Education

Universidade Estadual do Oeste do Parana, BSc in Computer Science, December 2007.

#### Experience

### Sainsbury's

Feb 2016 - Present

Go Developer

Main Technologies: Go, Ansible, Git;

Developing micro-services using Go programming language. I'm using ansible and vagrant to deploy the services, RabbitMQ to communicate between the services and Docker for my test environment.

Brandwatch Jul 2014 - Feb 2016

 $Linux\ Systems\ Administrator$ 

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Bareos, Ansible, Git;

A mix between software development (Python, JavaScript, HTML) and Linux Administration (Debian, Ansible, Puppet, Bareos Backup, Nagios, Sensu, LDAP).

DBA Dec 2013 - Feb 2014

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Raspberry PI and C;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop a system to analyse vehicle traffic on Brazilian highways. The product was develop using C, Python and Linux OS.

SEC+ Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

 $Software\ Engineer$ 

Main Technologies: Linux, Python, Django Framework, JavaScript and C;

Back-end development of web system for intelligent monitoring and management of natural disasters using Python and the Django framework. Front-end with Javascript (JQuery, Bootstrap, Google Maps API),bJSON, HTML5, CSS. Modeling and use of object-relational database and geographic objects with PostgreSQL/PostGIS.

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, C/C++, Java, ShellScript;

Member of the team responsible to design and develop the roadmap features of a product called Guardião used to intercept calls and internet trafic of people whose are being investigated by the police. Specifically allocated on the design and development of a module which main goal is to intercept the actions done on Facebook, WhatsApp and Hotmail of a target, using the gathered data to cross reference with another possible targets.

Main activities: C Development, Scripting, Linux administration, Network Packet Analysis (Wireshark), debugging and testing software.

## Digitro Technology - STE

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: Linux, VoIP, C/C++, shellscript, protocols: UDP, TCP, SIP;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop VoIP products such as IP phone and softphone. Most of the projects were developed in C ANSI language under Linux and Windows operating system.

Other activities involves: Linux administration, Python and Shell scripting, Network Packet analysis, debugging, profiling, code analysis, /etc.

Skills Base

 $Operating\ System:$  Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7 and OSX;

*Networkings*: TCP/IP protocol suite;

Progamming Languages: C/C++, Pascal, Python, Go, JavaScript, plus some experience with Lua and Java;

Virtualization: VirtualBox, VMWare, plus some experience with Xen;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

# Open Source Projects

- libpenetra: The libpenetra was created with the goal of studying the windows binary format known as Portable Executable (PE). With libpenetra you can access all information about PE binaries. (https://github.com/patito/libpenetra)
- libmalelf: The libmalelf is an evil library that SHOULD be used for good! It was developed with the intent to assist in the process of infecting binaries and provide a safe way to analyze malwares. (https://github.com/SecPlus/libmalelf)
- malelf: Malelf is a tool that uses librallelf to dissect and infect ELF binaries. (https://github.com/SecPlus/malelf)

More Info

- $\bullet \ \ \mathbf{Linkedin} \colon \mathbf{http://www.linkedin.com/in/benatto} \\$
- Github: https://github.com/patito